She has the best of both worlds... Now, she has to choose just one.
Hannah Montana: The Movie is a comedy, drama,
family film directed by Peter Chelsom.
When Miley Stewart (aka pop-star Hannah Montana) gets too caught up in the superstar
celebrity lifestyle, her dad decides it's time for a total change of scenery.
But sweet niblets!
Miley must trade in all the glitz and glamour of Hollywood for some ol' blue jeans on the family
farm in Tennessee, and question if she can be both Miley Stewart and Hannah Montana.
Miley Stewart / Hannah Montana, played by Miley Cyrus.
Robby Stewart, played by Billy Ray Cyrus.
Lilly Truscott, played by Emily Osment.
Ruby, played by Margo Martindale.
Jackson Stewart, played by Jason Earles.
Oswald Granger, played by Peter Gunn.
Hannah Montana: The Movie is a 2009 American teen musical comedy drama film
based on the Disney Channel television series Hannah Montana.
The film is produced by Walt Disney Pictures.
Directed by Peter Chelsom and written by Dan Berendsen, the film stars series regulars Miley Cyrus, Billy Ray Cyrus, Emily Osment,
Moises Arias, Mitchel Musso and Jason Earles, as well as Lucas Till, Vanessa Williams, Margo Martindale and Melora Hardin.
The film tells of how Miley Stewart's popularity and alternate celebrity persona begins to take over her life, so her father convinces
her to take a trip to her hometown of Crowley Corners, Tennessee to get some perspective on what matters most in life.
Hannah Montana: The Movie is the second theatrical film based on a Disney Channel Original Series after The Lizzie McGuire Movie (2003), and is the second theatrical
release of the Hannah Montana franchise, its predecessor Hannah Montana & Miley Cyrus: Best of Both Worlds Concert being released a year prior in 2008.
It is also the first, and so far only, theatrical film produced by It's a Laugh Productions and
Millar/Gough Ink, who is also known from producing the long-running hit series Smallville.
Filming began in April 2008, much of it occurring in Columbia, Tennessee,
and Los Angeles, California, and was completed in July 2008.
Hannah Montana: The Movie was released theatrically by Walt Disney
Pictures on April 10, 2009, in the United States.
Despite mixed reviews, the film achieved commercial success, grossing $169.2
million worldwide against a $30 million production budget.
The film explores themes of double life, countryside, pop star, musical, malibu.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.